Thelma Burnett Curley Kleinhans Collection Relating to Franklin D. Roosevelt
Thelma Burnett Curley Kleinhans Collection Relating to Franklin D. Roosevelt
1926-1962
Kleinhans, Thelma Burnett Curley.
16 items (SC)
Letters and memoranda
2466454
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1926 to 1962, the Thelma Burnett Curley Kleinhans Collection Relating to Franklin D. Roosevelt contains 16 items, including nine letters of the then trustee of the Georgia Warm Springs Foundation and future President of the United States. A memorandum written by former Surgeon-in-Chief LeRoy W. Hubbard certifies that in 1926 and 1927 Thelma Burnett was a member of the physiotherapy staff of the "center for the study and after-treatment of poliomyelitis (infantile paralysis)." The early Roosevelt letters thank Miss Burnett for her service at the center and indicate pleasure in securing her for subsequent periods after she had married and re-located to Syracuse, N.Y.
The letters after 1927 refer to Roosevelt's political campaigns, and a single letter (18 Oct. 1928) from Eleanor Roosevelt on behalf of the Democratic National Committee suggests:
"Perhaps you will go to hear my husband when he speaks in Syracuse, and you may find yourself more interested in Smith than you now are in Hoover. "
Letters which originated from the White House during the 1940s are signed by Private Secretary Grace G. Tully.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Georgia Warm Springs Foundation.; Physical therapy.; Poliomyelitis.; Correspondence.; Memorandums.; Physical therapists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mr. & Mrs. Joseph Spector and William Pearson Tolley
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - undated LeRoy W. Hubbard, M.D. memorandum: "To Whom It May Concern" (Sc 127)
  - undatedFranklin D. Roosevelt to Miss Burnett (Sc 127)
  - 1926 Aug. 24 Franklin D. Roosevelt to Miss Burnett (Sc 127)
  - 1926 Nov. 1 Franklin D. Roosevelt to Miss Burnett (Sc 127)
  - 1927 Jan. 24 Franklin D. Roosevelt to Miss Helena T. Mahoney (Sc 127)
  - 1928 Aug. 6 Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mr. and Mrs. John Curley ("Dear Jack and Thelma") (Sc 127)
  - 1928 Oct. 18 Eleanor Roosevelt to Mrs. John Curley ("Dear Mrs. Curley") (Sc 127)
  - 1928 Oct. 27 Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mr. and Mrs. John Curley ("My dear Curleys") (Sc 127)
  - 1930 Dec. 24 Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. John J. Curley ("My dear Thelma") (Sc 127)
  - 1932 July 16 Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. John Curley ("Dear Thelma") (Sc 127)
  - 1932 Aug. 2 Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. John Curley ("Dear Thelma") (Sc 127)
  - 1941 Oct. 23 Grace G. Tully to Mrs. Curley ("Dear Mrs. Curley") (photocopy) (Sc 127)
  - 1944 Jan. 14 Allen L. Dewey to Thelma B. Curley ("Dear Lt. Curley") (Sc 127)
  - 1944 Mar. 13 Grace G. Tully to Thelma B. Curley ("Dear Lieutenant Curley") (Sc 127)
  - 1944 Apr. 12 Grace G. Tully to Thelma Curley ("My dear Lieutenant Curley") (Sc 127)
  - 1962 Jan. 29 White House envelope to Mrs. Thelma Kleinhans, Executive Director, United Cerebral Palsy and Handicapped Children's Association of Syracuse, Inc. (Sc 127)